Guide to the Robert Flaherty Film Seminar Archive 1949 - 2011 MSS.326
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series II: Public TV, 253683
  - Public Television Seminar 1980 Tape 8, June 3, 1980; ID: 326.1014; 258962 (Box 21, Media ID: 326.1014)
    Years of Longing, Diego Echeria. Discussion with Jaime Barrio and Diego Echeria
    Spikes to Spindles, Chris Choy. Discussion with Alfred Guzzetti
    Also: The Cruz Brothers and Mrs. Malloy by Kathleen Collins
  - Public Television Seminar 1980 Tape 9, June 3, 1980; ID: 326.1015; 258970 (Box 21, Media ID: 326.1015)
    Continues from Tape 8
    The Cruz Brothers and Mrs. Malloy, K. Collins
    Also: Film: After the Earthquake by Lourdes Portillo with Ralph Maradiaga
    Also: Film: Billy in the Lowlands, discussion with Jan Egleson, David Luoy, Alfred Guzzetti
  - Public Television Seminar 1980 Tape 10, June 3-4, 1980; ID: 326.1016; 258971 (Box 21, Media ID: 326.1016)
    Continues from Tape 9 for ten minutes, then- June 4- VTR: "I don't matter, I don't care" Michael Marton
  - Public Television Seminar 1980 Tape 11, June 4, 1980; ID: 326.1017; 258972 (Box 21, Media ID: 326.1017)
    Continues from Tape 10
    Awakening by Larry Little Bird
    China: Land of My Father, Felicia Lowe
    Tule Indians by Eden Velez discussion also with Jaime Barrio
  - Public Television Seminar 1980 Tape 12, June 4, 1980; ID: 326.1018; 258973 (Box 21, Media ID: 326.1018)
    VTR Ancestors of those Unborn by George Burdeau, Discussion with George Horsecapture, Also SALSA by Jeremy Marre, Discussion with David Lacy
  - Public Television Seminar 1980 Tape 13, June 4, 1980; ID: 326.1019; 258974 (Box 21, Media ID: 326.1019, Case 326.1019_pt.1, Case 326.1019_pt.2)
    Film Clarence and The Angel by Bob Gardner discussion with Jaime Barrio and David Lacy
    Continues with The Laughing Alligator by Juan Downey, Discussion with Jaime Barrio, Continued on Tape 14
  - Public Television Seminar 1980 Tape 14, June 5, 1980; ID: 326.1020; 258975 (Box 21, Media ID: 326.1020)
    Ten Minutes on Juan Downey from Tape 13 (June 4th)
    Continues: Wyld Ryce and Heart of the Earth, Survival School, by Chris Spotted Eagles, discussion with George Horsecapture, Also: Unwanted by Luis Ruiz, Discussion with Ralph Maradiaga
  - Public Television Seminar 1980 Tape 15, June 5, 1980; ID: 326.1021; 258976 (Box 21, Media ID: 326.1021)
    Continued from Tape 14: Film Unwanted by Luis Ruiz
    VTR Real Indians by Paul Lucas and Statements by all Native Americans present.
    Note: Larry Little Birds song erased by request.
  - Public Television Seminar 1980 Tape 16, June 5, 1980; ID: 326.1022; 258977 (Box 21, Media ID: 326.1022)
    Film Loisaida by Marci Reaven and Beni Matias
    Discussion with Ralph Maradiaga
    Note: No Head Slate, Mistake of Short Mis-Recorded Section
    Also: To be young, gifted, and black by Gloria Mike Schultz
    Discussion with Gloria and David Lacy
  - Public Television Seminar 1980 Tape 17, June 6, 1980; ID: 326.1023; 258978 (Box 21, Media ID: 326.1023)
    Introduction: Jay Ruby, Barbara Van Dyke, Erik Barnouw, EVERYONE
  - Public Television Seminar 1980 Tape 18, June 6, 1980; ID: 326.1024; 258979 (Box 21, Media ID: 326.1024)
    Continued from Tape 17
    Group Evaluation
  - Arden House Evaluation Discussion 1, April 30, 1980; ID: 326.1040; 259017 (Box 21, Media ID: 326.1040)
  - Arden House Evaluation Discussion 2, April 30, 1980; ID: 326.1041; 259018 (Box 21, Media ID: 326.1041)
    Currenly Unavailable.
- Series III: Flaherty Israel, 253684
  This series contains audio recordings from the 1998 Flaherty Film Seminar in Israel, organized in collaboration with the New Foundation for Cinema and Television, Tel Aviv.
  - Flaherty Israel - Tape 2, 1998; ID: 326.1025; 268611 (Box 21, Media ID: 326.1025)
  - Flaherty Israel - Tape 3, 1998; ID: 326.1026; 258995 (Box 21, Media ID: 326.1026)
  - Flaherty Israel - Tape 4, 1998; ID: 326.1027; 258996 (Box 21, Media ID: 326.1027)
  - Flaherty Israel - Tape 5, 1998; ID: 326.1028; 258997 (Box 21, Media ID: 326.1028)
  - Flaherty Israel - Tape 6, 1998; ID: 326.1029; 258998 (Box 21, Media ID: 326.1029)
  - Flaherty Israel - Tape 7, 1998; ID: 326.1030; 258999 (Box 21, Media ID: 326.1030)
  - Flaherty Israel - Tape 8, 1998; ID: 326.1031; 259000 (Box 21, Media ID: 326.1031)
  - Flaherty Israel - Tape 9, 1998; ID: 326.1032; 259001 (Box 21, Media ID: 326.1032)
  - Flaherty Israel - Tape 10, 1998; ID: 326.1033; 259002 (Box 21, Media ID: 326.1033)
  - Flaherty Israel - Tape 11, 1998; ID: 326.1034; 259003 (Box 21, Media ID: 326.1034)
  - Flaherty Israel - Tape 12, 1998; ID: 326.1035; 259004 (Box 21, Media ID: 326.1035)
- Series IV: Film Council, 253685
  This series contains audio recordings from a 1974 meeting of the Film Council, a group of non profit film exhibition folks: librarians, museums and distributors in NYC, who met once a month to talk about non commercial film.
  - 1974 Film Council Symposium 1, March 23, 1974; ID: 326.1036; 259011 (Box 21, Media ID: 326.1036)
  - 1974 Film Council Symposium 2, March 23, 1974; ID: 326.1037; 259012 (Box 21, Media ID: 326.1037)
  - 1974 Film Council Symposium 3, March 23, 1974; ID: 326.1038; 259014 (Box 21, Media ID: 326.1038)
  - 1974 Film Council Symposium 4, March 23, 1974; ID: 326.1039; 259015 (Box 21, Media ID: 326.1039)
- Series V: Robert Flaherty Recordings and Other Seminar Related Material, 259020
  This series contains miscellaneous of audio material from various Film Seminars and activities.
  - "Morning Story" Comock The Eskimo Told by Robery Flaherty - Reel 1 of 2, circa 1949; ID: 326.0001; 277160 (Box 1, Media ID: 326.0001, Case 326.0001)
    Original Number: 2
    Robert Flaherty tells how he came to hear the story of Comock himself.
  - "Morning Story" Comock The Eskimo Told by Robery Flaherty- Reel 2 of 2, circa 1949; ID: 326.0002; 277161 (Box 1, Media ID: 326.0002, Case 326.0002)
  - Saturday Night Introductions, 1994; ID: 326.1042; 259021 (Box 21, Media ID: 326.1042)
  - Eric Barnouw Nanook Intro., 1994; ID: 326.1043; 259022 (Box 21, Media ID: 326.1043)
  - Mani Kaul, 1994; ID: 326.1044; 259023 (Box 21, Media ID: 326.1044)
  - Robert Drew, 1994; ID: 326.1045; 259024 (Box 21, Media ID: 326.1045)
  - Main Mic Retrospective, 1994; ID: 326.1046; 259025 (Box 21, Media ID: 326.1046)
  - Main Mic Retrospective Union Maids, etc., 1994; ID: 326.1047; 259026 (Box 21, Media ID: 326.1047)
  - Tiger 1, undated; ID: 326.1048; 259027 (Box 21, Media ID: 326.1048)
  - Tiger 2, undated; ID: 326.1049; 259028 (Box 21, Media ID: 326.1049)
- Series VI: Seminar and Administrative Papers, 260428
  This series contains the paper records of the Robert Flaherty Film Seminar Archive. It consists of packets and brochures handed out at the seminars, programs, press and publicity, planning, grant applications, and all papers pertaining to the daily operations of the organization. The papers have been arranged chronologically by year, and alphabetically within the year. Original folder titles have been maintained where possible.
  - 1946 - 1969, 260461 (Box 22)
  - 1970 - 1974, 260462 (Box 23)
  - 1974 - 1975, 260463 (Box 24)
  - 1976 - 1977, 260464 (Box 25)
  - 1978 - 1978, 260465 (Box 26)
  - 1979 - 1980, 260466 (Box 27)
  - 1980 - 1981, 260467 (Box 28)
  - 1981 - 1983, 260468 (Box 29)
  - 1983 - 1988, 260469 (Box 30)
  - 1989 - 1990, 260470 (Box 31)
  - 1990 - 1990, 260471 (Box 32)
  - 1990 - 1992, 260472 (Box 33)
  - 1993 - 1994, 260473 (Box 34)
  - 1994 - 1994, 260474 (Box 35)
  - 1995 - 1996, 260475 (Box 36)
  - 1996 - 1996, 260476 (Box 37)
  - 1996 - 1997, 260477 (Box 38)
  - 1997 - 1998, 260478 (Box 39)
  - 1998 - 1999, 260479 (Box 40)
  - 1999 - 2000, 260480 (Box 41)
  - 2000 - 2001, 260481 (Box 42)
  - 2001 - 2002, 260482 (Box 43)
  - 2002 - 2004; Undated, 260483 (Box 44)
  - Undated, 260484 (Box 45)
- Series VII: Financial Papers, 260429
  This series contains the financial papers of the Robert Flaherty Film Seminar Archive. It includes budget reports, tax papers, cancelled checks, bills, and all other financial material. The papers have been arranged chronologically by year, and alphabetically within the year. Original folder titles have been maintained where possible.
  - 1959 - 1973, 260488 (Box 46)
  - 1973 - 1975, 260489 (Box 47)
  - 1976 - 1977, 260490 (Box 48)
  - 1977 - 1978, 260491 (Box 49)
  - 1978 - 1979, 260492 (Box 50)
  - 1980 - 1981, 260493 (Box 51)
  - 1981 - 1982, 260494 (Box 52)
  - 1983 - 1985, 260495 (Box 53)
  - 1986 - 1988, 260496 (Box 54)
  - 1988 - 1989, 260497 (Box 55)
  - 1989 - 1990, 260498 (Box 56)
  - 1990 - 1991, 260499 (Box 57)
  - 1991 - 1992, 260500 (Box 58)
  - 1993 - 1993, 260502 (Box 59)
  - 1993 - 1994, 260503 (Box 60)
  - 1995 - 1996, 260504 (Box 61)
  - 1996 - 1997, 260505 (Box 62)
  - 1997 - 1998, 260506 (Box 63)
  - 1998 - 1999, 260508 (Box 64)
  - 1999 - 2000, 260509 (Box 65)
  - 2000 - 2001, 260510 (Box 66)
  - 2001 - 2002, 260511 (Box 67)
  - 2002 - 2003, 260512 (Box 68)
  - Tax papers, 1963-2003; 260513 (Box 69)
- Oversize Series VII: Seminar and Administrative Papers, 260837
  - "International Film Seminar Presents: 50 Years of the Flaherty" banner, Undated; 260838 (Box 72)
  - "Dark Circle" Film poster (2 copies), Undated; 260839 (Folder 9)